ZAFAR SALEEM

Contact

zafarsaleem3@gmail.com Mobile: +923248587783 WhatsApp: +16472474171

- https://github.com/zafarsaleem (Github)
- https://gitlab.com/users/ zsaleem/projects (Gitlab)
- https:// zafarsaleem.medium.com (Blog)
- https://zafarsaleem.github.io (Personal)

Top Skills

User Interface Developer HTML, CSS JavaScript, NodeJS

Publications

- Migrating Class Base
 Components to Functional
 Components Using React
 Hooks
- How to Setup User
 Authentication Using
 React, Redux and Redux
 Saga
- CSS Grid Layout
- How to perform CRUD operations using vanilla JavaScript
- Writing Scalable
 Architecture For Nodejs
- How to perform CRUD operations using React

Summary

Zafar has work experience as a developer on projects that spans from small scale websites to large scale applications both in small to large size companies within teams that consists team members belong to different cultural background and areas of expertise.

Experience

Timeoff TS

Developer Focus on React/Node

2017 - Present

Timeoff TS is a SaaS product that allows employees to setup vacations. I am working on it as a front end developer. I am responsible for its planning, designing and implementation phases.

- <u>saleem.github.io</u> (Personal) I designed and developed scalable, feature-rich web application using ReactJS and Redux.
 - I designed and developed the backend using NodeJS and ExpressJS.
 - I developed APIs using RESTful services built-in NodeJS.
 - I designed, developed and tested web and API solutions across the full web stack.
 - I establish and maintain technology standards, and evaluated new tools and techniques.
 - I setup development process and IT structure for the entire Timeoff TS Platform.
 - I setup continuous integration and continuous delivery pipelines and strategies.
 - I interview, onboard and technically train new team members to build the team.

Technologies: React, Redux, Redux Saga, JSX, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, RESTful API, JSON, Git, Github, Adobe Photoshop, CI/CD.

Capgemini

Software Consultant

2016 - 2016

The main focus of this project was to convert manual process of finding available consultants into digital process. In this position, I worked closely with user experience team to convert UI design and wireframes into working application.

- How to perform CRUD operations in Angular
- How I Setup My VIM as Modern Text Editor
- I coordinated with UI/UX team to translate the wireframe into high quality Angular codes.
- I coordinated with API engineers to develop well-structured front-end architecture.
- I troubleshooted and implemented bug fixes related to client reported issues.
- I developed web-based application using Angular that integrates with backend systems and RESTful services.
- I contributed to all aspects of the software development lifecycle including design, development, documentation and operations.

Technologies: Angular, Typescript, Angular Templates, CSS, Java, Spring, Scrum, Jira, Confluence, Git, Slack, Cl/CD.

MediaMonks Frontend Developer 2015 - 2016

Slimming World project offers convenient way to plan and manage users' diet. My main role was implementing the application from scratch and adding new features on front end side and fixing bugs and layout issues.

- I helped release and maintain code and debug production issues in Jira.
- I actively used Agile Methodology to optimise web and mobile application for maximum performance, speed and scalability.
- I collaborated effectively within a cross-functional organisation (including digital experts and developers) to prioritise, scope and communicate progress of deliverables.
- I participated in code reviews to ensure new code confirms to highest standards.

Technologies: React, Flux, JSX, CSS, Sass, .Net, MsSQL, Scrum, Jira, Git, Gitflow, Slack, Jenkins.

Schibsted Sverige Frontend Developer at SCM Ventures 2015 - 2015

I worked in a team to build new features for SCM Ventures classified sites i.e. Tayara and Corotos. I contributed into improving code quality and bring new tools such as Task Automation Tool to make the architecture more scalable.

- I worked with UI/UX designers to implement user-friendly solutions introduced new technologies into the team based on fit and suitability to deliver a solution.
- I collaborated with back end developers and UI/UX designers to improve usability.

- I troubleshooted and implemented bug fixes related to user reported issues.
- I was responsible for determining the structure and design of web pages, striking a balance between functional and aesthetic design and ensuring the web design is optimised for mobile pages.
- I built the appearance and user-interface of the classified sites, ensuring a seamless digital interface from a user's point of view.
- I was responsible for the digital platform's user-facing code and the architecture of the user experience, working closely with designers to bring wireframes from development to delivery.

Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Angularjs, Ruby on Rails, Grunt, jshint, Adobe Photoshop, Scrum, Jira, Confluence, Jenkins, Git, Skype.

Westwing Home & Living Frontend Developer 2013 - 2014

At Westwing I worked on westing's e-commerce site as a front end developer. I worked on improving the user interface and adding new features and fixing bugs.

- I developed, tested, and maintained responsive web/mobile apps with elegant UX that delight our users and raise their experience.
- I wrote clean and modular code that I was proud of, with extensibility and performance in mind.
- I worked in cross-functional teams with product managers, UX designers, backend developers and QA engineers to ship software on quality and on-time.
- I troubleshooted and implemented bug fixes related to product owner and user reported issues.
- I participated in code reviews to ensure new code confirms to highest standards
- I owned the products' interface implementation (HTML, CSS, presentational JS) and worked with other teams to maintain a style guide for others to reference.

Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Sass, HTML, Frontend Architecture, Grunt, jshint, Adobe Photoshop, Scrum, Jira, Confluence, Git, Skype, Jenkins, Google Analytics.

Eficode

Graphic User Interface Designer 2012 - 2012

I worked as a GUI designer for both web and mobile applications. I was part of agile development team where I implemented interactive user interfaces for web and mobile applications.

- I participated in full project life cycle from requirements gathering to project implementation, maintenance and support.
- I worked with project management and solution architects to estimate and scope out project.
- I worked with creative team during planning, discovery and production phase.
- I worked with backend development team to create and build solutions.
- I designed the whole web application using adobe photoshop.

Technologies: Adobe Photoshop, Fireworks, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, Scrum, Jira, Confluence, Jenkins, Git, Skype.

Demola

Web Developer

2011 - 2011

I worked on project called web based power of attorney as a web developer. I worked in an agile team that consists of front end team, backend team and design team.

Technologies: PHP, Codelgniter, MVC, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, MySQL.

Education

Northern University

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science (2005 - 2010)

Certifications

Cisco Certified Network Associate - CCNA (2008) Cisco Inc Certification

JavaScript Specialist (2016) Certification Partners (CIW)

Skills

Frontend:

React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Hooks, NextJS, Apollo Client, Microfrontend, Javascript, ES6+, TypeScript, Object Oriented JavaScript, BackboneJS, UnderscoreJS, jQuery, AJAX, Angular, RequireJS, Ionic, MVC, Material UI, Bootstrap, Styled-Components, CSS-in-JS, CSS, CSS3, SASS Pre-processor, CSS3 Media Queries, CSS Grid, Responsive Web Design, Mobile First Design, HTML, HTML5, JSX, Handlebars.

Testing:

Jest, Enzyme.

Backend:

NodeJS, ExpressJS, NPM, PHP, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, Android (GUI Designer i.e. xml) , JSON, RESTful API, Graph QL.

Version Control:

Git, Gitlab, Github, Bitbucket, Gitflow, Monorepos.

DevOps:

Heroku, AWS, Gitlab CI/CD, Github Actions, Jenkins, Grafana.

Tools

Lerna, Vim, Sublime, Eclipse, Photoshop, Chrome Dev Tools, Grunt, Bower, Webpack, Babel, Mac, Windows, Jira, Confluence, Scrum, Slack, Skype.

Languages

English

Urdu

Pashto